shaaditimes.com 2004-06-30

# Shaadi.com Matrimonials - The No.1 Matrimonial Services Provider - Privacy Policy

|  |    
|  Help Topics  
---  
Getting Started  
Login / Password  
Partner Search  
Profile Management  
Photographs  
Contacting Members  
Memberships  
Payment Options  
Newsletters  
Technical Issues  
Write to Customer Relations  

|    
|  |  |   
---|---|---  
Privacy Statement for Shaadi.com Matrimonial Services

[](https://www.truste.org/ivalidate.php?url=www.shaadi.com)People Interactive (India) Pvt. Ltd. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.shaadi.com. Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to our users’ privacy, we have agreed to disclose our privacy practices and have them reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please write to us. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or it is not satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe through the TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process (<http://www.truste.org/watchdog.html>). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve users concerns.

**Privacy Policy FAQs**

This section covers Shaadi.com's treatment of personally identifiable information that Shaadi.com collects when you are on our site.

Read on for information on the following aspects about our Privacy Policy:

1\.   What information does Shaadi.com collect/track about me?

2\.   What does Shaadi.com do with the information it collects/tracks?

3\.   With whom does Shaadi.com share the information it collects/tracks?

4\.   Tell me about links with other sites.

5\.   Tell me about Cookies.

6\.   Tell me about Shaadi.com policy on correcting, updating or removing personal information.

7\.   How will I know of changes in Shaadi.com privacy policy?

8\.   Tell me about security of my personal information.

9\.   Tell me about Shaadi.com's email policy.

10\.   Tell me how to contact Shaadi.com.

Please email us with questions regarding this statement.

|   
  
  Privacy Policy FAQs  
|  |   
  
|  1\.   What information does Shaadi.com collect/track about me?  
Shaadi.com is an online matrimonial service designed to provide an easy way for our members to meet each other on the Web. To accomplish this, our members create their own unique profiles and our matching technology provides them matches based on their pre-selected criteria. In order to do this, we ask for certain personal information which is displayed on the site. (This information includes physical / mental disability.) (Of course, all Shaadi.com visitors may browse the site, search member profiles and view any articles or features our site has to offer without entering any personal information.)Information Collected/Tracked by Shaadi.com

Shaadi.com gathers two types of information:  
1\. Information users submit; and  
2\. Information not directly submitted. 

  * Information users submitMEMBERS  
There are two types of user-submitted information we collect: Public and Private. We define Public information as personal information that may be displayed on the site at the behest of the member, such as gender, age, height, photograph, etc. Private information is defined as any information that allows others to contact a user other than through Shaadi.com or allows the collection of information about the user other than what is displayed on the site.Public: To accomplish our goal of bringing compatible people together, we must gather personal information, which may or may not include: customer-specified Shaadi.com username, gender, age, religion, income range, occupation, preference/lifestyle information, general geographic location and photograph.Private:This information is gathered from members and guests who apply for the various services our site offers. This information includes, but is not limited to: email address, first name, last name, credit card number or checking account information for payment, a user-specified password, mailing address, zip code and telephone number.

Shaadi.com also allows members to submit public and private information on behalf of others – child/ward, sibling or friend. If such child/ward, sibling or friend does not wish this information to be displayed, s/he has the option to request removal of such information after providing the necessary evidence that the information pertains to her/him.

SURVEYS & CONTESTS: From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, and age).SHAADI.COM AFFILIATE PARTNERS: The Affiliate Partner program is a vehicle for other websites to link to Shaadi.com. No personal member information is exchanged with the Affiliate Partner.
  * Information not directly submitted
AGGREGATE: This is information we collect that is not personally identifiable, such as browser type and IP address. This information is gathered for all users to the site. 
|   

| Back to top |   

|  2\.   What does Shaadi.com do with the information it collects/tracks?  
Shaadi.com uses the information it collects in the following ways: 

  * Information users submitMEMBERS  
Public: Public information supplied by members is intended to be viewed by visitors to the site. This information is used by visitors for searching and matching purposes. Public information cannot be used to identify a specific member by name, address, etc (except photograph, posting of which is voluntary).Private: We primarily use members’ email addresses to verify enrollment and to send system emails on behalf of other members. Email addresses are not disclosed to members. We may also use users’ email address to send news regarding our site, but the users may choose not to receive such emails by unsubscribing. Email addresses may also be used in private correspondence with the user for customer service issues. Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services. All other private information submitted by the user is confidential and is not disclosed except as required by law or to protect members of Shaadi.com. All private information can be updated or deleted by the user at any time, as follows:-Updating public information:
    * Login to your Shaadi.com account
    * Click on My Profile
    * Use Edit options in the page to update relevant information and submit
    * NOTE: To prevent misuse of the system, some information such as date of birth can be changed only on request. To do so, go to Help and use the Write to Customer Relations option.
Updating private information:
    * Login to your Shaadi.com account
    * Click on My Account
    * Update relevant information and submit
  
SURVEYS & CONTESTS: Contact and other information collected for contests is used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information collected is used to monitor or improve the site usage experience.SHAADI.COM'S AFFILIATE PARTNERS: Information submitted by the Affiliate Partner is used for establishing and maintaining a business relationship. No personal or business information is shared outside the relationship between Shaadi.com and the Affiliate Partner. Affiliate Partners may not view or access private information of Shaadi.com subscribers.OTHERS:
    * As a Shaadi.com user, you may ask queries to our experts in the field of beauty, health, relationships, legal, etc. Shaadi.com DOES NOT pass on your personally identifiable information to the experts. Even when your questions are published along with expert answers, we ensure that your identity is protected, by either changing your name or using first names only.
    * Shaadi.com allows members to write messages to other members to further the matchmaking process. While Shaadi.com exercises reasonable care to prevent site misuse, we strongly recommend you establish the authenticity and intent of members before giving out personally identifiable information in such messages.

  * Information not directly submittedAGGREGATE: We use your server, IP address, and browser-type related information in the general administration of our website.

|   

| Back to top |   

|  3\.   With whom does Shaadi.com share the information it collects/tracks?  
Except where you are expressly informed otherwise or as described immediately below, we do not sell, rent, share, trade or give away any of your personal information except to the financial institution that processes your credit card, or check transactions unless required by law, or for the protection of your membership.

If you register with Shaadi.com through one of our co-branded versions, your registration and profile information may be shared with the co-branding partner solely for the purpose of fulfilling the services provided by the co-branded site and any related promotional offers. Shaadi.com may tie-up with partners to bring you various services (e.g. Shaadi Shop). However, Shaadi.com will never share your personal information, without your express permission. Still, Wwe encourage you to review the privacy policy of the co-branded partner for questions about their use of yourany personally identifiable information and how you can modify or delete itthat you may separately submit to such partner.

|   

| Back to top |   

|  4\.   Tell me about links with other sites.  
Shaadi.com may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that Shaadi.com is not responsible for the privacy practices of other Web sites. We encourage you to be aware of this when you leave our site, and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by Shaadi.com. |   

| Back to top |   

|  5\.   Tell me about Cookies.  
Shaadi.com uses cookies to deliver various services and to keep track of your personal preferences. A cookie is a small text file that can be entered into the memory of your browser to:-  

* help a website recognize repeat users;
* facilitate the user's ongoing access to and use of the site;
* allow a site to track usage behavior;
* compile aggregate data for content improvements; and
* undertake targeted advertising.

If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, most browsers contain a function that allows a user to deny the cookie feature. You can also delete cookie files from your computer at your discretion. Please note that the use of cookies is a necessary part of the Shaadi.com technology and is necessary if you wish to access Shaadi.com. Disabling the cookie feature on your browser or deleting cookie files from your computer will render you unable to access certain features on Shaadi.com and participate in its services. Cookies may also be necessary to provide the user with certain features such as customized delivery of information. Consequently cookies we serve are tied to the user’s information.

Shaadi.com uses cookies to provide its services, to deliver content specific to your interests, to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit different pages on our site, and for other purposes. We do not and will not use cookies to collect private information from you!

Please note that cookies are used only to recollect information sent to your computer from Shaadi.com. We CANNOT access any information not sent by Shaadi.com.

Some of our business partners may use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies. 

|   

| Back to top |   

|  6\.   Tell me about Shaadi.com policy on correcting, updating or removing personal information.  
Shaadi.com allows you to modify or remove both public and private information from our database. |   

| Back to top |   

|  7\.   How will I know of changes in Shaadi.com privacy policy?  
If we change our privacy policy, we will prominently post a link to those changes on our Homepage so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify you by way of an email. We will give you a choice as to whether or not we can use information in this different manner and act accordingly. |   

| Back to top |   

|  8\.   Tell me about security of my personal information.  
Shaadi.com takes every precaution to protect your information, both online and offline.

When our registration/order process asks you to enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number), such information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL.

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect your information offline. All your information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, a billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information.

We have also done everything in our power to prevent misuse of photographs. Apart from not allowing photographs to be downloaded or copied, we have watermarked them with the Shaadi.com logo. This acts as a further deterrent for illegal use elsewhere.

If you have any questions about the security at our website, please email us.

|   

| Back to top |   

|  9\.   Tell me about Shaadi.com's email policy.  
We use email extensively to help you find your match on Shaadi.com. Our main email products and services include: 
* Member responses to your profile (called Contact Lens);
* Partner matches for you; and
* Newsletters updating you of the latest features on our site.

Occasionally, we may also send you: 

* Announcements of special events which Shaadi.com is associated with; or
* Special offers from partner sites, which we believe are useful for you.

As a Shaadi.com member, you are automatically subscribed to all of the above, as an integral part of our matchmaking services to you. However, at any time, you may choose to manage your subscriptions to one or more of the above (except Contact Lens). All our emails will carry a link to help you do this. You can also independently manage your email subscription using the  
My Email Manager option.

We reiterate that we will never sell / rent out your email address to any third party, unless you expressly permit us to do so. In fact, we do not allow ANYONE to see your email address, not even other Shaadi.com members.

Your friend's email address: Throughout Shaadi.com, you have the option to send interesting profiles / articles to your friends. Do make full use of this option, because your friends are also covered by Shaadi.com's spam-free privacy policy. We will use your friend's email address only to send your message to them. Then they will never ever hear from us again unless they voluntarily subscribe to our services.  |   

| Back to top |   

|  10\.   Tell me how to contact Shaadi.com.  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please email us or contact us at.Shaadi.com  
People Interactive (I) Pvt Ltd  
Shiv-e-Numh  
205, Dr Annie Besant Road  
Worli, Mumbai 400 018  
Phone: (91-22) 2495 2277  |   

| Back to top |   
  
|
